To protect my clan and friends,
为了守护战团和伙伴们
I must
我绝对
conquer Caird Labyrinth.
会成功攻略凯路德迷宫的
Rud.
路德
Lily?
莉莉？
I have a favour to ask.
我有事想拜托你
Ow…
好痛…
What's the big deal?
干嘛突然把我拉进来啊
THE STRONGEST TANK'S LABYRINTH RAIDS
《最强肉盾的迷宫攻略～拥有稀少技能体力9999的肉盾，被勇者队伍辞退了～》
Please help me with the straps on the back.
后面的绳子绑不起来 请帮我一下
There, all done.
好了 绑好咯
Thank you.
谢谢你
Now I can give Lilia a surprise service.
这样就可以给姐姐一个惊喜服务了
I see. I'll leave you to it then.
原来如此 那我回去咯
Wait.
请稍等一下
There's something else I want to ask you.
我还有一点事想问你
Rud, you…
路德你 那个…
You'll do your best
今后会作为战团团长
as a clan leader, right?
努力经营战团 对吧
Well, yes.
嗯 没错
You're amazing.
真厉害呢
I thought so when you made that declaration
你在大家面前宣布要攻略迷宫时 我就这么觉得了
I'm a coward.
因为我很胆小
I can't even tell other people the things I want to do.
根本不敢告诉任何人自己想做什么
Is there something you want to do?
你有什么想做的事吗
Promise you won't laugh?
你能保证不会取笑我吗
Promise.
当然
I don't have any grand goals like you,
我不像你 有那么远大的目标
but
只是
I don't want to let myself rely on Lilia all the time.
我希望自己不要老是依赖姐姐
I want to be able to stand on my own.
我想变成可以独当一面的人
When I'm with Lilia,
只要在姐姐身边
I never have to worry about anything.
我就不用为生活苦恼
Growing up, I've always been clumsy.
其实我从小就笨手笨脚
I always mess things up.
老是把事情搞砸
But Lilia would always be there for me.
但是 姐姐总会在我身边保护着我
Lilia is perfect
姐姐她真的很完美
and she can do anything.
而且很厉害 什么事都难不倒她
She's a fierce fighter.
战斗的时候也很勇猛
And I can only support her from the rear.
而我总是只能在后方支援她
Isn't that because you're good with magic?
那是因为你比较擅长魔法吧
Lilia can use magic too,
姐姐明明也可以用魔法
but she fights close combat.
但她却选择近战攻击
And when we use "Fusion",
而且 "融合"时
Lilia always takes control.
总是由姐姐担任主人格操控身体
I've never fought on my own.
我从没有自己战斗过
I see.
原来是这样啊
I always wondered
我确实一直很好奇
who took control when you guys fused.
你们融合时都是谁在操控身体
But
但是
I can't always depend on Lilia.
我不能总是这样依赖姐姐
I have things I want to accomplish by myself.
我想要自己完成自己想做的事
I see.
原来如此
That's why she approached me.
所以她才会突然跟我搭话吗
Given how close these sisters are,
她们姐妹俩的关系这么亲密
it is hard to tell the other that they want to be independent.
确实很难开口告诉对方 自己想学会独立呢
Lily, you can trouble me.
莉莉 你可以尽管给我添麻烦
Go ahead and go after what you want to do.
试着去做做看自己想做的事吧
Really?
真的可以吗
Then I'll get your help the next time I want to do something…
那我下次想做些什么时 就拜托路德帮忙…
Lily?
莉莉？
I thought I heard Rud…
我好像听到了路德的声音
Lilia.
姐姐
-Rud… -It's not what it looks like, Lilia!
-路德？ -不是的 莉莉亚
You've got it all wrong! This is a misunderstanding!
你误会了 这是一场意外
Can you come to the roof with me?
可以跟我来屋顶一趟吗
Is she going to push me off the roof?
我 等等会被推下去吗
What are you afraid of?
你在怕什么啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
I'd have thrown him off if it had been any other guy.
但今天如果不是你 我早就把对方推下去了
But you're not the kind of guy
因为对别人的宝贵妹妹出手 伤害她什么的
that would ever hurt my precious sister.
路德是不可能做出这种事的
That was just an act
刚才只是演技罢了
to get you out here.
这都是为了把你带出来
Have I told you about our past?
我有跟你说过 我们的过去吗
You said you were abandoned by your parents
你说你们被父母抛弃
and have been travelling with only each other since.
是靠互相扶持才走到现在的
Well,
不
rather than say we were abandoned,
与其说是被抛弃
it would be more accurate to say we ran away
正确来说 其实是因为父母会虐待我们
because we were being abused,
所以我们才从那边逃走了
mostly by our father.
尤其是父亲经常会虐待我们
So what happened earlier was a surprise.
因此 就算刚才真是一场意外
You're one of the few guys she can communicate normally with.
你也是少数可以 跟她正常交流的男生
That's why
正因如此
I wanted to talk to you.
我才想跟你聊聊
I want to take Lily
我希望总有一天
to a place where she can be happy.
可以带莉莉去一个 能让她打从心里感到幸福的地方
Until then, no matter what happens,
在那之前无论发生什么事
I swear to protect her.
我都会誓死守护她
I see.
这样啊
You two are very considerate of each other.
你们两人都很为彼此着想呢
Lily told me
莉莉刚才告诉我
she thought you were perfect and amazing.
她觉得姐姐是个完美又厉害的人哦
I'm not as good as she thinks I am.
我根本…没有她想得那么好
Right.
是啊
I don't think you're perfect either.
我也觉得你不是个完美的人
You lose your cool
该说只要牵扯到你妹妹
whenever your sister is involved.
你就会失去冷静吗
I've always thought of you as a bit of an oddball.
总觉得是个有点特异的人
I don't want to hear that from you.
我可不想被你这么说
Thanks for hearing me out.
谢谢你听我说这么多
You're my companion, after all.
毕竟你是我重要的伙伴啊
You can tell me if anything's bothering you.
如果有什么心事 随时都可以告诉我
I'll be counting on you when the time comes.
到时候就再拜托你了
When's Lilia coming back?
姐姐还不回来吗
Lilia, Lily, sorry to keep you waiting.
莉莉亚 莉莉 你们等很久了吗
Not at all.
没事
We just came back from the 49th floor.
我们正好刚从第49层回来而已
"ADVENTURER AT THE ENTRANCE" The 49th floor?
(站在入口的冒险者) 第49层？
Yes.
是的
"1ST FLOOR, 45TH FLOOR, 49TH FLOOR" I had the adventurer
(第1层 第45层 第49层) 我请迷宫调查员带我去一次
so I could use my "Dungeon Walk" to take everyone there directly.
这样我就能用我的"迷宫传送" 送大家过去了
You're a lifesaver, Lily.
莉莉 真是太谢谢你了
Not at all.
不会
Also,
顺带一提
the reason I didn't head straight to the 50th floor
之所以没有直接去第50层
was to assess the monsters' spawn rate.
是为了了解魔物的出现频率
I've gathered quite some intel on my end too.
我这边也收集到满多情报的
First, the party composition of the two clans.
首先跟你们报告一下 两大战团攻略迷宫时的小队成员
Black Dragon Fang
黑龙之牙那边
uses four attackers and two support and healers,
包括队长在内有四位攻击手
including the leader.
加上两位支援和辅助用的补师
White Tiger Claw uses four magic attackers
白虎之爪则是四位魔法攻击手
and two healers.
加上两位补师
In other words, both clans focus primarily on speed.
也就是说 这两支小队都比较重视速度
That's why they have their attackers double as tanks.
所以才会让攻击手 兼任肉盾的职责吗
Additionally, regardless of floor,
另外 不论在哪一层
it seems many of their members were inflicted with abnormal statuses.
他们似乎都有许多成员 陷入异常状态
"STRONG BODY" In that case, we can use
(强健肉体) 这样的话 应该可以用我的技能
my "Strong Body" to nullify the abnormal statuses.
"强健肉体"让异常状态无效化
This is going to be a challenging labyrinth,
虽然这个迷宫有些棘手
but no matter what, we have to break through to the 51st floor
但我们无论如何 都要突破到51层之后
and form an alliance with the two clans.
跟两大战团结盟才行
All right.
好的
I'll take the lead.
那我负责打头阵
Marius will take the rear.
玛里乌斯殿后
Luna will handle close combat.
露娜负责近战
Lilia, as usual, will move and act as she sees fit.
莉莉亚就跟平时一样 视情况自由行动
Nin will be responsible for restoring the shield force
妮恩负责回复护盾
and issue commands based on the situation…
并根据整体状况发布…
Is something the matter, Lily?
怎…怎么了吗 莉莉
Um,
那个
can I be the one to give commands during battle?
战斗时 可以由我来发布指令吗
Already trying to make a change?
这么快就想试着做出改变了吗
I understand.
我知道了
It might be easier for Lily, who takes the rear, to oversee the battle.
如果能由后卫的莉莉来发布指令 反而让人更容易理解
Then Lily will be the main commander.
那就以莉莉为主
Nin will support her.
妮恩负责辅助她
Got it.
知道了
I'm counting on you, Lily.
那就拜托你咯 莉莉
Sure.
好的
Okay, let's go.
那么 要出发咯
"Dungeon Walk"!
"迷宫传送"
This space doesn't favour those who rely on speed in combat.
这个空间对靠速度战斗的人 不太有利呢
But it's perfect for a tank like me.
不过对我这个肉盾来说 或许再好不过了
The spawn location set for the monsters is around here.
设置魔物的地方就在这附近
It would seem so.
好像真的在这附近呢
You can tell, too, Rud?
路德也分辨得出来吗
Only vaguely, though.
嗯 虽然只是隐约感觉得到
That's because you're the manager of Avancier Labyrinth.
因为你是阿凡锡亚迷宫的管理者啊
That's the reason?
原来是这样吗
They've set it up quite cleverly.
话说回来 对方配置得很巧妙呢
"ADVENTURER, SPAWN LOCATION" These two paths
(冒险者)(出现位置) 这两条左右分开的道路
lead to the same place,
虽然最终抵达的 地方都一样
but monsters will appear on both.
但两条路上都会出现魔物
So, for example, even if we take the left and encounter monsters,
比方说 如果我们在左边战斗
the monsters from the right will come at us from behind.
那右边的魔物 就会从后方追过来
So, they're trying to trap us?
所以对方是想夹击我们吗
Exactly.
正是如此
The guardian here
这里的守护者
is a cunning one.
可能是个相当狡猾的人
It's the Poison Lizard!
是毒蜥蜴
The Black Owl is coming from the right!
右边过来的魔物是黑鸮
"Sacrificial Shield"!
"牺牲之盾"
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
Poison gas?
是毒雾？
Sorry,
不好意思
but abnormal statuses won't work on me.
异常状态对我可没用
It blocked the attack with its magic.
它用魔力挡下攻击了吗
More Black Owls!
又来了好几只黑鸮
Rud,
路德
we can take them,
虽然我们应该能打败它们
but we shouldn't waste energy here.
但还是不要硬留在这边 跟它们对战了
You're right.
说得也是
You guys keep going.
你们先继续往前走
Leave this to me.
这里交给我就好
Got it.
是
Everyone, this way!
各位 往这里
Flash magic stone!
闪光魔法石
Lily, your commands were on point.
莉莉 你下达的指示很不错哦
They were easy to understand.
真的非常容易理解呢
I'll continue to do my best.
接下来我也会全力以赴的
By the way, I just realised something.
话说 我刚才发现一件事
Rud's Sacrificial Shield,
路德的牺牲之盾
I think we can decide whether to transfer the damage to you or not.
好像可以由我们这边决定 是否要将损耗的护盾转移到你身上
Yes, I noticed that too.
是的 我也发现了
We couldn't do that before.
之前明明没办法自己决定的
Your skill level must have gone up
难道是和我战斗过后
after you fought me!
技能就强化了吗
Maybe…
或许是吧
It's all thanks to me!
那就是我的功劳吧
That means we can disable the damage absorption
这样不想让路德背负伤害时
whenever we want.
就可以自己解除技能了呢
But Rud's skills are certainly something.
不过 路德的能力很异常呢
It's rare to see a tank
能完美引开魔物的肉盾
that can perfectly distract the enemy.
可不常见哦
That's true.
确实如此
I used to think all tanks could do that.
我还以为肉盾基本上 都做得到这种事呢
Rud's just on a completely different level.
路德实在太厉害了
Even if you say that…
就算你们这么夸我…
It'd be great
如果路德之后
if you could pick up the "Self Recovery" skill too.
也能用"自我回复"的技能就好了
That sounds like another difficult thing.
你又突然提出那么困难的要求
Does such a skill even exist?
真的有那种技能吗
What? So humans don't know about this?
什么啊 人类不知道吗
"Humans"?
你说"人类"…
Are you not one yourself?
难道你不是人类吗
Um, not entirely?
呃 应该不完全是吧
Incidentally,
这么说起来
we don't really know much about you.
我们确实不太清楚你的事呢
That's true.
对啊
We risked our lives to fight you last time,
虽说曾经赌上性命跟你拼死一战
but now you're not giving off any malicious intent,
但现在完全无法从你身上 察觉一丝危险的气息
so it completely slipped our minds.
所以就忘记问你了
Marius,
玛里乌斯
if you don't mind, would you tell us more about yourself?
方便的话 可以跟我们说说你的事吗
Only what you're comfortable with, of course.
当然 只要说你想说的部分就好
I was worried whether or not you guys would accept me.
我不确定你们是否能接受我的身份
Actually…
其实…
I am a demigod.
我是魔人
A demigod?
魔人
Yes.
没错
Broadly speaking,
以广义上来看
the world consists of humans and demihumans.
我们的世界分为人族和亚人族
It is said that in the past, there were even demigods.
据说在更早之前 还有魔人族
Demigods and demihumans do not differ much in appearance,
魔人和亚人在外观上并无差异
but instead of god,
但他们不像人类一般敬仰神明
they worship the devil. That's why they are known as demigods.
而是誓死效忠魔神 因此被称为魔人
That's the gist of it.
简单来说就是这样
I can oversee the labyrinth because I am a demigod.
也正因为是魔人 所以才能管理迷宫
What does that mean?
这是什么意思？
You didn't know?
你们不知道吗
It may seem as if humans are benefitting from labyrinths,
虽然现在看来 就像人类在利用迷宫谋取好处
but labyrinths were created by the devil
但迷宫其实
to destroy the human world in the first place.
是魔神为了摧毁人类世界 才创造出来的
What?
什么
So, labyrinths
原来迷宫…
weren't created by god to enrich our lives?
不是神明大人为了让人类 过上丰饶的生活才创造出来的吗
Where did you get that from?
那种说法是从哪里来的啊？
Well, that fits the legend.
罢了 这就跟传说很像呢
Indeed.
是啊
There might have been those that knew the truth in the past.
或许以前真的有人知晓这些事实
Anyway, that's the story.
总之事情就是这样
So, this labyrinth must be guarded by a demigod too,
因此这个迷宫 肯定也是交给某个魔人管理
and a strong one at that.
而且还是个相当厉害的强者
So, you better be careful when you challenge the guardian.
所以跟守护者对战时 还是小心一点比较好
We get that,
我知道了
but wouldn't that make them kind of like your brethren?
不过魔人对你来说 应该就像同胞吧
Are you really okay with that?
这样没问题吗
I hate those guys.
我讨厌那些家伙
If I have to live like this,
如果要以这种方式活下去
I'd rather not be a demigod.
那我不想当一个魔人
Instead, I want to defeat them as Marius.
而是想作为玛里乌斯打倒他们
I see…
这样啊
Sorry.
抱歉
I had my own motives
我其实是为了自己的目标
for coming to this labyrinth with you guys.
才跟你们一起来攻略这个迷宫的
Well,
在我心中
I consider you a friend too.
你姑且也算是我的伙伴
So, I'm counting on you.
所以 今后也拜托你咯
I have no objections as long as you don't hurt Lily.
只要不会危害到莉莉 我就没有任何意见
I'll pretend I heard nothing.
刚才那些话 我也会当作没听到的
Same here.
我也是
We're friends as long as
只要你不会伤害姐姐
you don't hurt Lilia.
你就是我们的伙伴
I expected that.
就知道你们会这样
All right. I'm in too.
好吧 我也同意
Me too.
我也是
Aren't you glad?
太好了呢
I owe it all to you.
这都是多亏了你啊
Thanks, Rud.
谢谢你 路德
Um…
那…那个
Lily?
莉莉？
Sorry to ruin the mood,
抱歉在气氛正好的时候打扰各位
but I'd like to discuss the strategy
我想跟大家讨论一下
to deal with the monsters on the 50th floor.
该如何与第50层会出现的魔物战斗
Of course. I'll leave it to you.
好 那就拜托你了
Yes.
好的
First, the lizard.
首先是蜥蜴
I think we should play it safe…
我认为应该保守一点…
We fought off the monsters
后来我们
as they appeared and progressed.
一边击退出现的魔物 一边向前迈进
Finally, we reached the 50th floor.
总算抵达第50层
There it is! The Bone Dragon!
出现了 是骸骨龙
Everyone, let's do this!
各位 要上咯
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
"Taunt" was effective.
"挑衅"的效果很好
We should be able to proceed according to Lily's plan.
应该可以照着莉莉拟定的计划行动
"ALL BONES, BONES FOR WINGS TOO" According to the information
(全身都是骨头 翅膀也是骨头) 根据第50层会出现的魔物…
"FOUR LEGS, LONG TAIL" about the Bone Dragon,
(四只脚 尾巴很长) 骸骨龙的情报看来
it will frequently use abnormal status skills.
它应该会频繁使出异常状态技能
That may disrupt our formation,
这可能会使我们的阵形遭到破坏
so Rud will go in and block it first.
所以路德先过去挡住它
The rest of the party should stay out of its range.
其他成员不要进到它的攻击范围内
Understood.
知道了
Lilia and Marius will attack from outside its range.
姐姐和玛里乌斯 从它的攻击范围外进行攻击
It's a bone monster,
因为它们是骸骨魔物
so it's better
比起用砍的
to attack it by smashing it rather than cutting it.
用击碎的方式攻击 效果应该比较好
Got it.
我知道了
Mhm.
嗯
Also, it's weak to fire.
另外 它的弱点是火属性
We should enchant our weapons with fire before attacking it.
我认为应该先将武器附加火属性 再进行攻击
We should use mainly fire magic too.
魔法也以火魔法为主
In addition,
此外
once the Bone Dragon's HP is reduced to a certain amount,
一旦将骸骨龙的体力 削减到某种程度
its body will…
它的身体就会…
Rud!
路德
Thanks, Lily.
谢谢你 莉莉
Don't mention it.
不会
Taking cover under its wing is a no-go.
不可以躲在翅膀正下方呢
I'll have to be cautious before I make my move too.
移动前可能也要稍微注意一下
Master!
主人
It's okay, Luna.
别担心 露娜
He left himself be pushed back to put distance between them.
他是刻意以那种方式被弹开 借此拉开距离的
It is faster than I expected.
它的动作比我想象中还快
And this puts me too far from my party.
而且这样跟大家离得太远了
Thanks, you two.
两位 不好意思
No problem. I've been trying to get pumped up.
没事 我正想大闹一场呢
Good. Let's keep this up.
很好 以这股气势打倒它吧
Its attacks are fast and powerful,
虽然它的每一击都又快又沉
but as long as we watch closely and be careful,
但只要看清楚 做好准备
we should be fine.
应该就不会有问题
What's going on?
怎么回事
A ranged attack?
范围攻击？
Are you guys all right?
你们没事吧
It was a slight wound,
虽然只是稍微擦伤
but I seem to have been poisoned.
但我好像陷入毒系的异常状态了
Same.
我也是
Nin,
妮恩
heal them while I distract it.
趁我引开敌人时 帮他们治疗一下
Got it.
知道了
Luna, heal them with me.
露娜 跟我一起帮他们治疗
Yes.
是
Take this!
吃我这招
We know you're weak to fire.
我们可是知道你怕火哦
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
What? That thing…
什么 这家伙…
It ignores "Taunt"
如果一直遭受攻击
when it is continuously attacked
就会无视"挑衅"
and starts attacking randomly.
开始随机攻击吗
Rud, it's coming!
路德 它要攻击了
I think my shoulder is dislocating…
肩膀快要脱臼了
My shield feels so heavy.
盾变得好重
What's with this stuff?
这个泥是怎么回事？
Someone cast water magic!
谁来帮我施个水魔法
The stuff is stuck on my shield, and I can't move it…
这些泥土紧粘在上面 完全用不下来
This stuff is weighing down my shield…
因为这些泥土 盾牌变得太重了
Rud!
路德
Thanks for that, Nin.
抱歉 妮恩
This is turning into a battle of endurance.
不过这下 似乎要变成长期战了呢
In that case…
这样的话…
What's that?
那是什么
An automatic recovery area.
那是自动回复区
It's a saint skill that only Nin can use.
只有妮恩可以使用 是圣女技能之一
You can treat abrasions just by standing there.
站在那里就能治疗外擦伤
All set up.
我设置好了
Make the most of it.
记得好好利用哦
Got it.
好
ONE HOUR LATER
(一个小时过后)
This thing is still going…
这家伙还不死吗
What?
怎么回事
This is the thing Lily mentioned…
这是莉莉说过的…
Its "flame" is coming!
"炎"要来了
Everyone, take cover!
大家快躲起来
Rud?
路德？
Rud!
路德
Master!
主人
Why are you guys surprised?
你们在惊讶些什么啊
You think you can burn me to a crisp with that?
以为我会就这样被烧成木炭吗
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
The successive attacks
因为被连续攻击
have depleted 5,000 shield force.
已经消耗掉5000护盾了
This is not looking good.
这下不太妙
You were a bold one.
你刚才还挺大胆的嘛
I'll kill you as you wish.
我就如你所愿 杀了你吧
Now!
趁现在
It's working.
效果很好
Just a little more and we should be able to defeat it.
再一下下 肯定就能打败它了
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
Thank you, Rud!
路德 谢谢你
This is just…
对我们来说 这里…
a stepping stone for us!
只是一个过渡点
"Life Conversion"!
"生命转换"
It's the Bone Dragon's drop.
是骸骨龙的素材
Finally, it's over…
终于打倒了
Congratulations on breaking through the 50th floor.
恭喜你突破第50层
Thanks.
谢谢
But
不过
I don't think we're in any shape to continue further.
这种状况下实在说不出 要继续攻略第51层呢
Yeah.
是啊
Let's call it a day.
今天就到此为止吧
Rud,
路德
I think we should hold off
关于今天得到的素材
selling the loot we got today for now.
我觉得先不要卖掉比较好
Otherwise, news of our raid might get out.
否则我们攻略得很顺利的消息 可能会走漏出去
You have a point.
你说得对
Then we'll sell them another time.
那就改天再一起卖吧
Lily,
莉莉
the instructions you gave
你连回城后的指示 也下达得很完美呢
Um…
那…那个
I'll do my best for the next floor too.
到了下一层 我也会加油的
Now, as customary, let's celebrate!
那就依照惯例 去庆功一下吧
Yes!
好的
I'll pass.
今天我就不去了
I'm a little tired.
因为有点累
I want to rest early.
所以我想早点回去休息
I'll head back too.
那我也回去了
See you tomorrow, everyone.
各位 明天见